Azaz -Ul Haq PMI-ACP, CSM

Lahore, Pakistan | P: +92 331 4356169 |

Summary

I have 5 years of experience in implementation of Quality Assurance, Software Testing, Automation Testing and Deployment life cycle. I have hands on experience in requirement gathering and analysis, Test effort estimation, Test planning, Test Design Matrix, Test case development and execution, Reviews, Software Quality Audits, Tasks Allocation, Tracking and Reporting. Hands on experience in working on Sauce Labs that manages the Cross Browser Testing and can be embedded with Automation Frameworks. I had been managing QA environments through AWS. Strong mentoring skills, capable of leading and motivating individuals to maximize productivity, exceptional communicator focused on building strong relationships with peers and clients. Proactive, Efficient in multi-tasking and decision making, known for achieving best quality and on time delivery. Highly motivated individual with excellent management, Leadership and analytical skills and Responsible individual who believes in continuous improvements.

Certification

- **❖ PMI-ACP**[®] in 2020
- Certified ScrumMaster® in 2022
- Certified Agile Tester in 2019
- ISTQB Foundation Level certified in 2016

Professional Experience

1. Strategic Systems International

Designation: Principal Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Duration: August 2019 - Present

2. NetSol Technologies Lahore

Designation: Principal Software Quality Assurance Engineer

Duration: September 2017 - August 2019

3. Strategic Systems International

Senior Software Quality Assurance Engineer Designation:

Duration: March 2016 - August 2017

Education

BS (Hons.) Computer Science

2011 - 2015

Lahore Pakistan

Skills

SQA

Jira

Test Management

CMMI Documentation

CMMI Audits

SQL

Sauce Labs

Team Server Foundation

Project Plan

Test Plan

Postman

Jenkins

Bloomrpc

GIT

JMeter

Katalon

Selenium

API Testing

Trainings

Appium